A Guide to the Rockefeller Foundation records, projects, SG 1.1, Series 300 Latin America - Series 833 Lebanon FA386b
Rockefeller Archive Center
- France, 1916-1959; 500; 13 Cubic Feet; 32 __Boxes __13 cubic feet
  Grants to French institutions were made primarily in the medical sciences field. The earliest grants were awarded for the campaign against tuberculosis, from which the Foundation's nursing program was created. The University of Paris was the major recipient of grants for the medical sciences. Funds were given for work by Th. Alajouanine, Jean Scherrer, and Clovis Vincent in neurology and neurosurgery and by Georges Heuyer in psychiatry. Funding was given to the Radium Institute in the 1920's, 1930's, and 1940's. The University of Lyons and the University of Strasbourg were also recipients of a relatively large number of medical sciences grants. In addition, there are files dealing with the Pearce report on French medical education which was part of a report on medical education throughout the world.
  The Rockefeller Foundation also gave funding to a full range of humanities and social sciences programs. A large number of grants were given for work in philosophy. Grants were also given for a broad range of studies including art history and geography and ethnology. A number of humanities and social sciences grants were made to refugee scholars, including Richard Alewyn (German Literature), Elias Bickermann (Greek archeology), Kurt Sachs (music history), Julius Lewy (Assyriology), and Paul Schrecker (Philosophy).
  The American Library in Paris and the Bibliotheque Nationale also received Foundation support.
  500 (no program letter; general material which does not fit into a particular program area)
  500 A Medical sciences (research conducted in medical schools or medical research institutes, research directly applicable to the mental and physical health of human beings)
  500 C Nursing (nursing education, public health nursing)
  500 D Natural sciences and agriculture (research usually conducted in departments outside of medical schools, research in pure science, veterinary medicine or agriculture)
  500 J Public health demonstrations, local health units
  500 K Health services (epidemiology, reform, public health administration, laboratories, vital statistics, and particularly sanitary engineering)
  500 L Public health education (schools of hygiene and public health)
  500 O Yellow fever
  500 P Undulant fever
  500 R Humanities and arts
  500 S Social sciences
  500 T Tuberculosis
  - Carrel, Alexis, 1939-1945, 1948, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Carrel, Alexis, 1939-1945, 1948, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Gounelle, Hugues - (Nutrition Institute, Paris) - (Supplies), 1948 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Pasteur Centenary, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - France - Medical Sciences, 500.A
    - (Medical Sciences), 1918, 1920-1930, 1932, 1937-1938, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - (Medical Sciences) - (A-Z), 1932, 1935, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 0005a)
    - Ambroise Pare Hospital - Roudinesco, Jenny - (Children's Clinic, Travel Grant), 1947-1950 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Clinic for Child Psychiatry, Lyons - Thevenin, Lise - (Travel Grant), 1949-1950 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - College de France, Paris - Alloiteau, Jean-Jacques - (Physiological Chemistry, Equipment), 1947, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - College de France, Paris - Endocrinology - (Courrier, Robert), 1938-1941, 1943-1945 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - College de France, Paris - Endocrinology - (Courrier, Robert), 1938-1941, 1943-1945 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Cournard, Andre - (Visit, Physiology), 1945-1950 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Fessard, A.E. - (Neurophysiology), 1937-1938, 1940-1941, 1946-1955 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Fessard, A.E. - (Neurophysiology), 1937-1938, 1940-1941, 1946-1955 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Fessard, A.E. - (Neurophysiology), 1937-1938, 1940-1941, 1946-1955 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Medical Literature Aid, 1945-1948 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Pasteur Institute, Paris, 1921-1926 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Pasteur Institute, Paris - Beck, Adolf and Chargoff, Erwin - (Virus Diseases), 1933-1936 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Pasteur Institute, Paris - Du Nouy, Lecomte - (Biophysics, Equipment), 1929-1931 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - PEA Pearce, Richard M. "Medical Education in France" Volume I, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - PEA Pearce, Richard M. "Medical Education in France" Volume II, 1925 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Philomathic Society of Paris - Neurophysiology, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Social Medicine, 1939-1940 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Stahl, Jules - (Travel Grant, Clinical Medicine), 1946-1948 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - University of Bordeaux - Neuropsychiatry - (Delmas-Marsalet, Paul; Travel Grant), 1948-1949 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - University of Lille - Endocrinology - (Tuchmann-Duplessis, Herbert; Books), 1949 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - University of Lyons - Faculty of Medicine - (Appropriations), 1925-1933 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - University of Lyons - Faculty of Medicine, 1923-1928 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - University of Lyons - Faculty of Medicine, 1923-1928 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - University of Lyons - Faculty of Medicine, 1929-1938, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - University of Lyons - Faculty of Medicine, 1929-1938, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - University of Lyons - Faculty of Medicine, 1929-1938, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - University of Lyons - Histology, 1931, 1936, 1945-1950 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - University of Lyons - Physiology - (Herman, H.), 1944 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - University of Lyons - Policard, A. - (Travel Grant), 1945-1948 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - University of Lyons - Psychiatry - (Lepine, Jean, Neuropsychiatry), 1937-1938 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - University of Lyons - Riese, Walter - (Refugee Scholar, Neuropsychiatry), 1933, 1935-1937 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - University of Lyons - Surgery - (Leriche, Rene), 1932 (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - University of Lyons - Surgery - (Mallet-Guy, Pierre), 1948-1953 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - University of Marseilles - Cardiology - (Gerard, Raymond, Equipment), 1948-1954 (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - University of Marseilles - Neurobiological Laboratory - (Mosinger, Michel), 1936-1942, 1948-1950 (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - University of Marseilles - Neurobiological Laboratory - (Mosinger, Michel), 1936-1942, 1948-1950 (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - University of Marseilles - Pathology - (Cornil, Lucien), 1936-1938, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - University of Marseilles - Physiology - Benoit, Paul H. (Equipment), 1948-1951 (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - University of Marseilles - Surgery - (Metras, Henri), 1947-1950 (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - University of Montpellier - Cardiology - (Girard, Gaston, Equipment), 1949-1951 (Box 5, Folder 45)
    - University of Nancy - (Institute of Hygiene, Building Improvements), 1925-1929, 1931 (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - University of Paris - Anesthesia - (du Bouchet, Nadia; Equipment and Supplies), 1946-1947, 1949 (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - University of Paris - Bernard, Leon - (Public Health Administration, Travel Grant), 1922 (Box 5, Folder 48)
    - University of Paris - Cardiology - (Carlotti, Jacques; Lenegre, Jean), 1948-1950 (Box 5, Folder 49)
    - University of Paris - Genetics - Lezine, Irene - (Travel Grant), 1948 (Box 5, Folder 50)
    - University of Paris - Histological Laboratory - (Champy, Christian), 1934-1941, 1943, 1947-1948 (Box 5, Folder 51)
    - University of Paris - Kleinmann, Hans - (Refugee Scholar, Physiological and Pathological Chemistry), 1933-1939 (Box 5, Folder 52)
    - University of Paris - Medical Faculty, 1920-1929 (Box 5, Folder 53)
    - University of Paris - Medical Faculty, 1920-1929 (Box 5, Folder 54)
    - University of Paris - Medical Faculty, 1920-1929 (Box 5, Folder 55)
    - University of Paris - Medical Faculty, 1930-1939 (Box 6, Folder 56)
    - University of Paris - Medical Faculty, 1930-1939 (Box 6, Folder 57)
    - University of Paris - Medical Faculty - Visits, 1939-1941, 1944-1948 (Box 6, Folder 58)
    - University of Paris - Medical Faculty - Visits, 1939-1941, 1944-1948 (Box 6, Folder 59)
    - University of Paris - Medical Faculty - (Working Papers), 1924-1930 (Box 6, Folder 60)
    - University of Paris - Medical Library, 1928-1930, 1932 (Box 6, Folder 61)
    - University of Paris - Medical Records - (Labbe, Marcel), 1926-1933, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 62)
    - University of Paris - Neurology, 1931, 1933-1940 (Box 6, Folder 63)
    - University of Paris - Neurology - (Alajouanine, Th.; Scherrer, Jean), 1949-1952 (Box 6, Folder 64)
    - University of Paris - Neurosurgery - (Vincent, Clovis), 1936-1941, 1945-1952 (Box 6, Folder 65)
    - University of Paris - Neurosurgery - (Vincent, Clovis), 1936-1941, 1945-1952 (Box 6, Folder 66)
    - University of Paris - Parasitology - (Brumpt, Emile), 1925-1928, 1930-1940, 1945-1948, 1951-1952 (Box 7, Folder 67)
    - University of Paris - Parasitology - (Brumpt, Emile), 1925-1928, 1930-1940, 1945-1948, 1951-1952 (Box 7, Folder 68)
    - University of Paris - Parasitology - (Brumpt, Emile), 1925-1928, 1930-1940, 1945-1948, 1951-1952 (Box 7, Folder 69)
    - University of Paris - Pathology - (Roussy, Gustave; Baudoin, Alphonse), 1926, 1928, 1931-1933, 1937-1941 (Box 7, Folder 70)
    - University of Paris - Pediatrics, 1925-1926, 1938-1940 (Box 7, Folder 71)
    - University of Paris - Pediatrics - (Debre, Robert, Travel Grant), 1944-1949 (Box 7, Folder 72)
    - University of Paris - Pharmacology - (Tiffeneau, Marc), 1926, 1929-1936 (Box 7, Folder 73)
    - University of Paris - Physiology - (Monnier, A. M.), 1930-1937, 1946-1950 (Box 7, Folder 74)
    - University of Paris - Physiology - (Monnier, A. M.), 1930-1937, 1946-1950 (Box 7, Folder 75)
    - University of Paris - Psychiatry - (Santenoise, Daniel, Travel Grant), 1925, 1935-1936 (Box 7, Folder 76)
    - University of Paris - Psychiatry - (Heuyer, Georges), 1948-1951 (Box 8, Folder 77)
    - University of Paris - Public Health Teaching, 1935-1937, 1939-1940 (Box 8, Folder 78)
    - University of Paris - Radium Institute, 1921, 1929-1941, 1945-1946 (Box 8, Folder 79)
    - University of Paris - Radium Institute, 1921, 1929-1941, 1945-1946 (Box 8, Folder 80)
    - University of Paris - Radium Institute, 1921, 1929-1941, 1945-1946 (Box 8, Folder 81)
    - University of Paris - Radium Institute - Reports, 1930-1938; 7 Items (Box 8, Folder 82)
    - University of Strasbourg - Biochemistry - (Nicloux, Maurice; Grabar, Pierre, 1931-1936 (Box 8, Folder 83)
    - University of Strasbourg - Endocrinology - (Klein, Marc, Travel Grant), 1946, 1948-1950 (Box 8, Folder 84)
    - University of Strasbourg - Histology - (Bouin, Pol), 1931-1938, 1941, 1943, 1946, 1949 (Box 8, Folder 85)
    - University of Strasbourg - Hygiene and Social Medicine - (Oberling, Charles), 1937-1939 (Box 8, Folder 86)
    - University of Strasbourg - Medical School, 1919-1924 (Box 8, Folder 87)
    - University of Strasbourg - Medical School, 1925-1928 (Box 9, Folder 88)
    - University of Strasbourg - Medical School - Report, 1922 (Box 9, Folder 89)
    - University of Strasbourg - Medical School - (Callot, Jacques, Travel Grant), 1949-1950 (Box 9, Folder 90)
    - University of Strasbourg - Obstetrics - (Ginglinger, Albert, Travel Grant, 1949-1950 (Box 9, Folder 91)
    - University of Strasbourg - Surgical Clinic, 1947-1949 (Box 9, Folder 92)
    - University of Strasbourg - (A-Z), 1935 (Box 9, Folder 93)
    - University of Toulouse - Anesthesiology - (Rieunau, Mme. Dr. Georges), 1948-1950 (Box 9, Folder 94)
    - University of Toulouse - Physiology - (Bugnard, Louis Camille), 1934, 1936-1938 (Box 9, Folder 95)
    - University of Toulouse - Physiology - (Laporte, Yves), 1947-1952, 1955, 1958 (Box 9, Folder 96)
  - France - Nursing, 500.C
    - (Nursing), 1919-1928 (Box 9, Folder 97)
    - ADA-1 Adams, Gladys A. "The Polyvalent Nursing Service of the City of Montpellier", 1927 (Box 9, Folder 98)
    - Central Bureau of Nurses, 1924-1930, 1933 (Box 9, Folder 99)
    - CRO-1 Crowell, F. Elizabeth "Nursing Education and Hospital Service in France", 1921 (Box 9, Folder 100)
    - Florence Nightingale School of Nursing, Bordeaux, 1919, 1924, 1926, 1946 (Box 10, Folder 101)
    - Florence Nightingale School of Nursing, Bordeaux, 1919, 1924, 1926, 1946 (Box 10, Folder 102)
    - Salpetriere Hospital - (Nursing Education), 1922-1923, 1925 (Box 10, Folder 103)
    - Secretan Dispensary - (Nursing Education), 1925-1927 (Box 10, Folder 104)
    - University of Lyons - Nursing School, 1920, 1924-1941 (Box 10, Folder 105)
    - University of Lyons - Nursing School, 1920, 1924-1941 (Box 10, Folder 106)
    - University of Lyons - Nursing School, 1920, 1924-1941 (Box 10, Folder 107)
    - WIL-1 Williams, Linsly Rudd "Memo on Training Schools for Public Health Visitors in France", 1920 (Box 10, Folder 108)
  - France - Natural Sciences and Agriculture, 500.D
    - College de France, Paris, 1932 (Box 10, Folder 109)
    - College de France, Paris - Embryology - (Faure-Fremiet, E.), 1935-1937, 1939 (Box 10, Folder 110)
    - College de France, Paris - Joliot, Frederic - (Physics), 1934-1941, 1943-1946 (Box 10, Folder 111)
    - College de France, Paris - Joliot, Frederic - (Physics), 1934-1941, 1943-1946 (Box 10, Folder 112)
    - College de France, Paris - Joliot, Frederic - (Physics), 1934-1941, 1943-1946 (Box 10, Folder 113)
    - College de France, Paris - Nordheim, Lothar Wolfgang - (Mathematical Physics), 1933-1934 (Box 11, Folder 114)
    - Gautheret, Roger J. - (Plant Biology), 1946-1949 (Box 11, Folder 115)
    - Higher Education - Donzelot, Pierre - (Travel Grant), 1950 (Box 11, Folder 116)
    - Institut Henri Poincare, Paris - (Borel Emile; Colloquia), 1938-1939, 1941 (Box 11, Folder 117)
    - Institut Henri Poincare, Paris - (Travel Grants), 1946, 1948-1952 (Box 11, Folder 118)
    - Marine Biological Stations, Roscoff and Banyuls, 1927-1932, 1934, 1946-1947, 1958 (Box 11, Folder 119)
    - National Center of Scientific Research, Paris - (Scientific Literature), 1938-1941, 1944-1945 (Box 11, Folder 120)
    - National Center of Scientific Research, Paris - (Scientific Literature), 1938-1941, 1944-1945 (Box 11, Folder 121)
    - Pasteur Institute, Paris - Agricultural Biology - (Simonet, Marc, Equipment), 1933-1935 (Box 11, Folder 122)
    - Pasteur Institute, Paris - Biochemistry - (Equipment), 1937, 1939-1941, 1948-1952 (Box 11, Folder 123)
    - Pasteur Institute, Paris - Biochemistry - (Equipment), 1937, 1939-1941, 1948-1952 (Box 11, Folder 124)
    - Pasteur Institute, Paris - Protistology - (Lwoff, Andre M.), 1935-1936, 1939-1940 (Box 11, Folder 125)
    - Rapkine, Louis - (Cell Chemistry, Travel Grants), 1945-1946 (Box 11, Folder 126)
    - Rothschild Institute, Paris - (Wurmser, Rene; Faure-Fremiet E.; Ephrussi, Boris), 1935-1940, 1942, 1944 (Box 12, Folder 127)
    - University of Bordeaux - Physiological Chemistry - (Genevois, Louis), 1932, 1934-1935 (Box 12, Folder 128)
    - University of Lyons - Atomic Physics - (Thibaud, Jean), 1935, 1938-1941, 1945-1946 (Box 12, Folder 129)
    - University of Lyons - Atomic Physics - (Thibaud, Jean), 1935, 1938-1941, 1945-1946 (Box 12, Folder 130)
    - University of Lyons - Biochemistry - (Fromageot, Claude), 1930, 1932-1941, 1944-1950 (Box 12, Folder 131)
    - University of Lyons - Biochemistry - (Fromageot, Claude), 1930, 1932-1941, 1944-1950 (Box 12, Folder 132)
    - University of Lyons - Psysiology - (Gardot, H.; Equipment), 1934 (Box 12, Folder 133)
    - University of Marseilles - (Chevallier, A., Physics), 1935-1938 (Box 12, Folder 134)
    - University of Montpellier - Zoology - (Chatton, Edouard, Equipment), 1932, 1934-1935 (Box 12, Folder 135)
    - University of Paris - Ecole Normale Superieure - Zoology - (Teissier, Georges; L'Heritier, P.), 1938-1941 (Box 12, Folder 136)
    - University of Paris - Embryology - (Giroud, A.), 1949-1950 (Box 12, Folder 137)
    - University of Paris - Endocrinology - (Gayet, Rene), 1935-1936 (Box 12, Folder 138)
    - University of Paris - Experimental Cytology - (Moricard, Rene), 1936, 1938-1940 (Box 12, Folder 139)
    - University of Strasbourg - Biochemistry - (Boivin, Andre, Equipment), 1946-1949 (Box 12, Folder 140)
    - University of Strasbourg - Physiology - (Terroine, Emile F.), 1931, 1935-1939 (Box 12, Folder 141)
  - France - Public Health Demonstrations, 500.J
    - (Public Health Demonstrations), 1920, 1926-1932 (Box 13, Folder 142)
    - Aisne - (Departmental Helath Service), 1927-1929, 1931 (Box 13, Folder 143)
    - Basses-Alpes - (Health Demonstration), 1929-1930 (Box 13, Folder 144)
    - Finistere - (Health Demonstration), 1926-1927, 1929-1930 (Box 13, Folder 145)
    - Herault - (Health Demonstration), 1922, 1924-1929, 1931 (Box 13, Folder 146)
    - Saone-Et-Loire - (Health Demonstration), 1926-1931 (Box 13, Folder 147)
    - Seine-Et-Marne - (Health Demonstration), 1926-1933 (Box 13, Folder 148)
    - Tarn-Et-Garonne - (Health Demonstration), 1926-1930, 1932 (Box 13, Folder 149)
  - France - Health Services, 500.K
    - Vital Statistics, 1928 (Box 13, Folder 150)
  - France - Public Health Education, 500.L
    - National Office of Social Hygiene, 1922, 1924 (Box 13, Folder 151)
    - National Office of Social Hygiene, 1925-1934 (Box 14, Folder 152)
    - National Office of Social Hygiene, 1925-1934 (Box 14, Folder 153)
  - France - Yellow Fever, 500.O
    - International Office of Public Hygiene - Yellow Fever, 1930-1936, 1938-1939 (Box 14, Folder 154)
    - International Office of Public Hygiene - Yellow Fever, 1930-1936, 1938-1939 (Box 14, Folder 155)
    - Pasteur Institute, Paris - Steranoppulo, Georges T. - (Yellow Fever Studies), 1933-1939 (Box 14, Folder 156)
  - France - Undulant Fever, 500.P
    - (Undulant Fever), 1930-1936 (Box 14, Folder 157)
    - (Undulant Fever), 1930-1936 (Box 14, Folder 158)
    - TAY-1 - TAY-10 Taylor, Richard M. Reports, 1931-1935; 10 Items (Box 15, Folder 159)
  - France - Humanities and Arts, 500.R
    - American Library in Paris - Historical Record - Volume I - ALP, 1922-1935 (Box 15, Folder 160)
    - American Library in Paris - Historical Record - Volume II - ALP, 1922-1935 (Box 16, Folder 161)
    - American Library in Paris, 1936-1944 (Box 16, Folder 162)
    - American Library in Paris, 1936-1944 (Box 16, Folder 163)
    - American Library in Paris, 1936-1944 (Box 16, Folder 164)
    - American Library in Paris, 1936-1944 (Box 16, Folder 165)
    - American Library in Paris, 1936-1944 (Box 16, Folder 166)
    - American Library in Paris, 1945-1948 (Box 17, Folder 167)
    - American Library in Paris, 1945-1948 (Box 17, Folder 168)
    - Association des Professeurs de Langues Vivantes, Paris - (English Teachers), 1947-1949 (Box 17, Folder 169)
    - Bibliotheque Nationale, Paris, 1926, 1928-1941 (Box 17, Folder 170)
    - Bibliotheque Nationale, Paris, 1926, 1928-1941 (Box 17, Folder 171)
    - Bibliotheque Nationale, Paris, 1926, 1928-1941 (Box 17, Folder 172)
    - Bibliotheque Nationale, Paris, 1926, 1928-1941 (Box 17, Folder 173)
    - Bibliotheque Nationale, Paris, 1942, 1944-1947 (Box 18, Folder 174)
    - Carpentier, Pierre and Madeleine - (Visit, English Language), 1945-1948 (Box 18, Folder 175)
    - Catel, Jean - (American and Canadian Literature, Travel Grant), 1944-1946 (Box 18, Folder 176)
    - Catholic Institute, Toulouse - Von Hildebrand, Dietrich - (Philosophy), 1939-1940 (Box 18, Folder 177)
    - College de France, Paris - Far Eastern Studies - (Mus, Paul) - Travel Grant, 1948-1950 (Box 18, Folder 178)
    - College de France, Paris - Latin American Studies - (Bataillon, Marcel, Travel Grant), 1947-1949 (Box 18, Folder 179)
    - Giraud, Marcel - (American Civilization, Travel Grant) - (College de France, Paris), 1945-1948 (Box 18, Folder 180)
    - French Historians - Historical Record - FH, 1929-1930 (Box 18, Folder 181)
    - Humanities Survey - (Bruner, Jerome S.; Brown, John L.), 1945-1947 (Box 18, Folder 182)
    - Humanities Survey - (Bruner, Jerome S.; Brown, John L.) - HUSU-1a, 1945-1947; 1 Item (Box 18, Folder 183)
    - Le Breton, Maurice - (American and Canadian Literature, Travel Grant), 1944-1946 (Box 18, Folder 184)
    - Philosophy - Ames, Van Meter - (Travel Grant ), 1947-1950 (Box 19, Folder 185)
    - Philosophy - Farber, Marvin - (Travel Grant), 1947-1951 (Box 19, Folder 186)
    - Philosophy - Rice, Philip - (Travel Grant), 1947-1951 (Box 19, Folder 187)
    - Pouinard, Alfred - (National Museum of Canada) - (French Folk Song in North America), 1947-1950 (Box 19, Folder 188)
    - University of Bordeaux - Albornoz, Claudio Sanchez - (Spanish History), 1938-1940 (Box 19, Folder 189)
    - University of Dijon - Marck, Siegfried - (Philosophy, Refugee Scholar), 1934-1939 (Box 19, Folder 190)
    - University of Nancy - Equipment - (Audio-Visual), 1948-1949 (Box 19, Folder 191)
    - University of Paris - Alewyn, Richard - (German Literature, Refugee Scholar), 1933-1935 (Box 19, Folder 192)
    - University of Paris - Bickermann, Elias - (Greek Archeology, Refugee Scholar), 1933-1935, 1937-1939 (Box 19, Folder 193)
    - University of Paris - Friedmann, Wilhelm - (Romance Philology, Refugee Scholar), 1933-1940, 1959 (Box 19, Folder 194)
    - University of Paris - Grautoff, Otto - (Art History, Refugee Scholar), 1933-1934, 1936 (Box 19, Folder 195)
    - University of Paris - Lewy Julius - (Assyriology, Refugee Scholar), 1933 (Box 19, Folder 196)
    - University of Paris - Liebreich, Anna - (Art History, Refugee Scholar), 1933-1935, 1937 (Box 19, Folder 197)
    - University of Paris - Marck, Siegfried (Philosophy, Refugee Scholar), 1933 (Box 19, Folder 198)
    - University of Paris - Sachs, Kurt - (Music History, Refugee Scholar), 1933-1935, 1937 (Box 19, Folder 199)
    - University of Paris - Schrecker, Paul - (Philosophy, Refugee Scholar), 1933-1940 (Box 19, Folder 200)
    - University of Strasbourg - Canguilhem, Charge de Cours - (Philosophy), 1948-1949 (Box 19, Folder 201)
  - France - Social Sciences, 500.S
    - (Social Sciences), 1929-1933, 1935, 1939-1940 (Box 20, Folder 202)
    - Bibliotheque de Documentation Internationale Contemporaine - Hintze, Hedwig - (Bibliography, Refugee Scholar), 1933-1935 (Box 20, Folder 203)
    - Centre D'Etudes de Politique Etrangere, Paris, 1931-1952 (Box 20, Folder 204)
    - Centre D'Etudes de Politique Etrangere, Paris, 1931-1952 (Box 20, Folder 205)
    - Centre D'Etudes de Politique Etrangere, Paris, 1931-1952 (Box 20, Folder 206)
    - Centre D'Etudes de Politique Etrangere, Paris, 1931-1952 (Box 20, Folder 207)
    - Centre D'Etudes de Politique Etrangere, Paris, 1931-1952 (Box 20, Folder 208)
    - Centre D'Etudes de Politique Etrangere, Paris, 1931-1952 (Box 20, Folder 209)
    - Centre D'Etudes de Politique Etrangere, Paris - Reports, 1935-1940; 6 Items contained in folders 210-211 (Box 21, Folder 210)
    - Centre D'Etudes de Politique Etrangere, Paris - Reports, 1935-1940; 6 Items contained in folders 210-211 (Box 21, Folder 211)
    - Centre D'Etudes de Politique Etrangere, Paris - Gottmann, Jean - (Geography, Travel Grant), 1948-1949 (Box 21, Folder 212)
    - Commission for Coordination of French Institutes, Paris - (International Relations), 1932-1935 (Box 21, Folder 213)
    - Ecole Coloniale, Paris - (African Ethnography, Labouret, H.), 1932 (Box 21, Folder 214)
    - French Committe for Study of Pacific Relations, Paris, 1936 (Box 21, Folder 215)
    - Institut de Droit Compare, Paris, 1931-1935, 1939, 1944-1946 (Box 21, Folder 216)
    - Institut de Droit Compare, Paris, 1931-1935, 1939, 1944-1946 (Box 21, Folder 217)
    - Institut International de Droit Public, Paris, 1929-1936 (Box 21, Folder 218)
    - Institute of Economic Research, Paris, 1930-1936 (Box 21, Folder 219)
    - Institute of Economic Research, Paris, 1930-1936 (Box 21, Folder 220)
    - Institute of Economic Research, Paris, 1930-1936 (Box 21, Folder 221)